I believe everyone has recently seen the term
always see a term
cloud skills
Skills
Its current popularity is no less than that of the prompts PROMP back in the day.
So today in this video
I will give you a comprehensive understanding of what cloud skills really are
What tasks can it help us accomplish?
compared to prompts and MCP
what exactly is the difference
Why do I think its potential is enormous
Let's cut to the chase
Let's get started
First, let's briefly introduce in plain language
What are cloud skills
To help everyone understand,
Let's use a story as an example
For example, in the workplace,
You are the company's boss
AI is the top graduate you've recruited from a prestigious university
His IQ is very high
has strong comprehension skills
smooth-talking
can chat with you about anything
but when you actually ask him to do the work
His biggest issue is never about IQ
but is unfamiliar with your company's way of doing things
nor any practical experience
And the prompt is like you standing beside him
on-the-spot verbal instructions
He can complete the task according to your requirements every time.
The quality is also good.
But it naturally has a drawback
once you close this conversation
he forgets what you just talked about
so the prompt
targets the temporary instructions you currently provide
only takes effect in this round of conversation
But skills are more like on his first day at work
you gave him a very detailed internal company operations manual
It is more like a Knowledge repository folder
which can include standardized scripts, templates
reference materials, etc.
This way, the AI can
can invoke it automatically
So you can think of skills as a toolkit for AI
skill pack
a reusable operational manual
teach it what tasks to perform
what tools to use and what standards to follow
This way, it can determine when to invoke them
where to invoke
These steps can all be automatically completed for you in the background.
Before the advent of cloud skills
When we perform some repetitive tasks
such as writing emails
make plans
when writing articles
Every time you chat with AI, you have to re-enter the prompts
The output results not only lack consistency
it also wastes a lot of our time
You might think
Can't we just use the project feature with prompt commands?
That's right, most people think the same way.
But in fact, there are two fundamental problems.
Firstly, these operational steps cannot be replicated.
For example, the next time you need to plan an activity
unless you plan it within this project
Otherwise, you'll have to repeat all the steps
organize all the matters that need attention
re-enter it into the AI
The second issue is
These planning steps cannot be stacked either
For example, you have a folder specifically for task A
another one is specifically for task B
but you cannot directly combine them
collaborate on new tasks
Because these two folders operate completely independently
so you have to open many different folders
and the efficiency is also not high
And this is exactly why we need to use skills.
Unlike traditional project folders
cram all the processes and resources into a single project
Cloud will extract these processes
packaged into so-called skills
In skills
You can include all sorts of things
such as prompts
So,
In essence, skills are simply a
a folder that stores workflows and data centers
rather than just a simple text
Once you understand this logic,
you can use skills to create various workflows
such as a workflow to help you send mass emails
market research handbook
a template handbook for designing company bylaws
And most importantly,
they are not independent
can also be combined and used together
So this is why
I think skills are helping us achieve improvements in work efficiency
a core node
as long as you master this skill
your work efficiency and flexibility
will be significantly higher than before
And all you really need to do is one thing
those repetitive workflow tasks you usually perform
transform into replicable skills packages
and then when you need to use it
just give a command
So theoretically, all repetitive tasks
or some tasks that have been troubling you for a long time
In fact, all these tasks can be automated for you using skills.
high-quality completion
Another concept that often causes confusion is
the difference between skills and MCP project
Let's take cloud as an example
The cloud itself serves as the brain of AI
is the core of AI decision-making
skills are the instruction manual for cloud
Let me tell you
how to perform each specific task
While MCP is not responsible for teaching people how to work
He is only responsible for issuing access cards to people.
Because no matter how powerful the AI is
but if it doesn't have permission
cannot access your company's database
it simply cannot solve practical problems
And the MCP is like the access card
enables AI to securely connect to external systems
It can also incidentally invoke its capabilities
such as creating files
access the database
The project is a dedicated workspace for AI
can integrate skills
MCP tools and your existing Knowledge base
help you focus on completing a specific task
Believe it
After listening to the explanation above
Now you must clearly understand skills prompt
the difference between MCP and project
And this is exactly what's called the skills
the main reason for the recent high praise
Because you can tailor it according to your specific work needs
freely combine and match
You don't need to use all the tools in every process.
Because they are not competing with each other
What you're actually doing is building this workflow process
When we explain what we need to do to Cloud in plain language
At this point, it will start scanning
see which skill package can accomplish this task
and then find the skills related to your needs
after matching and invoking
with the pre-saved operational manual in the system
start helping you process tasks
The great thing about this design is that
Moreover, a single task can simultaneously invoke multiple skills.
For example, we want it to help us
First, analyze a two-hour podcast video
and then generate a related presentation PPT for us
At this point, Cloud will find in its skills package
can match the analysis of the video
and the two skills needed to generate the PPT
Do you know what this means?
That is to say, the more types of skills you have
the more things it can help you do
If possible
You can invoke a large number of skills for a single task.
Additionally, I've summarized for everyone
Currently, there are three types of skills available on Cloud for you to use.
First, if you've never heard of skills before
Then I suggest you start off by
you don't need to create your own skills right away
You can first try out ANEROBIC, the parent company of cloud
The official has open-sourced a skills repository
The repository contains many highly practical skills.
You just need to go to the function in Settings
Here, just make sure that
The code execution and file creation functions here are already enabled
you can control the cloud right here
which skills to use in the chat
When you scroll down
Your custom skills will be displayed here
When you click on the example skill next to it
This is the official cloud open-source skills repository
Skills designed for various workflows
I personally don't recommend you open too many skills at once
because having too many skills enabled
Cloud may make mistakes when executing workflows
You just need to open those that you actually need to use.
Also, let me tell you
If you want to use the cloud skills feature
you need to at least subscribe to their
the $20 Pro plan is required
Also, there is no Chinese option in the Cloud Settings.
So if you find English difficult to understand,
you can download an immersive translation plugin
you can directly view the Chinese version
Additionally, the officially open-source skills repository
The URL has also been provided in the description box for you.
The second type is what we just mentioned
custom skills
that is, the skills you create based on your personal needs
This can be your own workflow
template of instruction resources
even code scripts
you just need to follow the official required format
prepare your own skills file and upload it
you can successfully activate them
If you're not a professional programmer
no problem
You just need to enable the skill creator here
which means letting skills teach you how to create skills
The third type is the skills on third-party community platforms.
Now on GITHUB, there are also many cloud
skills created by users themselves
some have been favorited thousands of times
Its advantage is the wide variety of options available
compared to the categories provided officially
Here you can find many
skills tailored for niche needs
However, here we also need to remind everyone
When using these community skills, be mindful of security
Moreover, there is no clear evaluation system for the skills here.
According to aerobic
once you enable skills
as long as the context is appropriate
it will be triggered automatically
So my suggestion is
add the following custom command in the Settings
add it to your personal preferences here
ensure that Cloud activates the correct skills when responding
Similarly, this custom command is also placed in the description field.
Just now we introduced to everyone
the many functions that skills can perform
So when do we really need to create skills?
I suggest you ask yourself these three key questions
First, is this task highly repetitive?
Do you need to do this every time you interact with the AI?
have to keep repeating the same instructions
sending the same prompt every time
The second point
In reality, do you also need to train someone
to familiarize with this process and standard
Third, does the AI's output for you each time
requires ensuring quality or format consistency
If the above three questions
you have two options
then I would suggest you design your skills
Additionally, if you're using the $20 per month Pro version
It has a weekly usage limit.
So I suggest that
you only create skills for your most frequently used workflows
avoid wasting tokens
Although skills
Initially, it was just a small functional module within the cloud.
but in recent months
More and more people find it particularly useful
so codex cursor
Open cos these AI programming tools have gradually started supporting skills
And on December 18th last year,
Aerobatic also officially released Agent Skills
released as an open standard
To be honest, I still feel that
The value of skills is greatly underestimated.
For example, you can build a data analysis tool
This way, it can assist you from data collection to data analysis
and finally generate charts
reduce the workload from 3 to 4 hours down to about 10 minutes
Or you can also create a tool that helps summarize long videos
summarization tool
especially for those one-to-two-hour podcasts
You don't need to watch them from beginning to end
You just need to use skills to build a workflow for you
can summarize all the core points in the video
What are the key points inside
are worth focusing on
Whether you are a professional programmer
turn your experience and workflows into various skills
or a programming novice like me
encapsulate your work requirements into skills
for future use
I think the potential of skills is enormous.
Just as MCP has transformed the way we design AI workflows
just like with AI agents
And I think it's not just Cloud, other large language models
will likely adopt this concept very soon
So in the next few days
I will continue to delve deeper into the usage of cloud skills
and then share with you how to practice step by step
help you transform from a novice to a master of practical skills
If you haven't subscribed to the channel yet,
Follow us now
If you found this video helpful
Welcome to like and subscribe to the channel
See you in the next video, bye-bye